JOE DAVIS

07758245829 | peterdavis.joe@gmail.com

Web: https://github.com/JoeDavisGithub

Professional Summary

Knowledgeable software engineering professional with experience building, testing and deploying scalable and modular software products. Organised and hardworking team player. Uses strong interpersonal skills to work well with internal and external stakeholders to meet project technical requirements.

Having studied Computer science for 3 years at University I am looking for opportunities to further develop myself professionally as a Software Engineer. I have been working with Government funded contracts over the past year to further upskill myself and gain valuable experience within Software Design and engineering.

Work history

Freelance Software Engineer

Sep 2019 - May 2023

Local Business

- Improved office efficiency for brand sale events by approximately 20% by writing a program in Python to keep track of stock and sales using MySQL
- Assisted in organising packaging by dedicating staff to certain tasks and structuring the storage layout to make accessing items efficient.

Waiter Mar 2022 - Sep 2022

Braza Restaurant

- Effectively prioritized tables in high-stress environments, ensuring superior client satisfaction
- This led to a 15% boost in overall customer contentment
- Demonstrated effective communication with clients, for example being called upon to deescalate customer tensions and drive promotion/sale of new items
- Led and organised a team of 4 waiters resourcefully during peak hours.

Junior IT Technician Jul 2018 - Jul 2018

Elevate

- Resolved Technical issues for office staff, including file recovery after crashes and setting up new workstations to enhance productivity
- Produced reports on data inconsistencies and technical resolutions, this included documenting workstation specifications and software or unaccounted expenses.

Technical skills

- Python, Java, C++, CSS, HTML, PHP, SQL, JavaScript
- Linux, Windows

- Anaconda, Visual Studio, VS Code, IntelliJ, Git, Google Cloud Platform, AWS, Jupyter Notebooks, Spyder, Apache, MySQL, Oracle VirtualBox
- Tkinter, Pandas, SciPy, NumPy, Matplotlib

Education

First Class bachelor's degree in computer science – City University London

Project and achievements

- Cloud-based web application, PHP, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, AWS (S2, EC2)
- Using Al models to predict property value, Python (Pandas, scikit-learn, NumPy, Matplotlib)
- Educational Tool, Python (Tkinter, csv)
- 2D Platformer, Java
- Code Academy
- Java Boot-camp